const question = document.getElementById("question");
const selections = Array.from(document.getElementsByClassName("question-text"));
let squidQuestionCounter = document.getElementById("squidQuestionCounter");
const Squidscore = document.getElementById("Squidscore");

console.log(selections);

let currentQuestion = {};
let selectingAnswers = false;
let score = 0;
let questionCounter = 0;
let availableQuestions = [];
let Squidtimer = 100;
let questions = [
    {
      question: "Which mask shape had the highest authority?",
      choice1: "circle",
      choice2: "Square",
      choice3: "star",
      choice4: "triangle",
      answer: 2
    },
    {
      question: "What color was the mask worn by 'The Front Man'?",
      choice1: "Dark-Blue",
      choice2: "Gold",
      choice3: "Purple",
      choice4: "Black",
      answer: 4
    },
    {
      question: "What number did Oh Il-Nam/the old man wear on his jacket?",
      choice1: "001",
      choice2: "422",
      choice3: "677",
      choice4: "998",
      answer: 1
    },
    {
        question: "How much Won/Money would the final player win?",
        choice1: "70 million won",
        choice2: "200 billion Won",
        choice3: "45.6 billion Won",
        choice4: "1 trillion Won",
        answer: 3
      },
      {
        question: "What are the four candy shapes in game 2 '?",
        choice1: "Circle, Star, Triangle, Umbrella",
        choice2: "Triangle, Rectangle, Hexagon, Square",
        choice3: "Umbrella, Star, Hexagon, Swirl ",
        choice4: "Square, Triangle, Star, Spiral",
        answer: 1
      },
      {
        question: "How many episodes are in season one?",
        choice1: "6",
        choice2: "22",
        choice3: "9",
        choice4: "15",
        answer: 1
      },
      {
        question: "What is the one thing all players had in common?",
        choice1: "They were all childless",
        choice2: "They all suffered from an illness",
        choice3: "They were all from China",
        choice4: "They all had Debt",
        answer: 4
      },
      {
        question: "What was the name of the fourth game?",
        choice1: "Hop Scotch",
        choice2: "Squid Game",
        choice3: "Tug of War",
        choice4: "Marbles",
        answer: 4
      },
      {
        question: "How many players make it to game 6?",
        choice1: "2",
        choice2: "5",
        choice3: "7",
        choice4: "9",
        answer: 1
      },
      {
        question: "Which of these is the correct order in Squid Game?",
        choice1: "Squid Game, Tug of War, Red Light, Green Light, Marbles, The Glass Game, Ppopgi/Dalgona",
        choice2: "Red Light, Green Light, Ppopgi/Dalgona, Tug of War, Marbles, The Glass Game, Squid Game",
        choice3: "Ppopgi/Dalgona, Red Light, Green Light, Marbles, Tug of War,The Glass Game, Squid Game, ",
        choice4: "Red Light, Green Light, Tug of War, Marbles, Ppopgi/Dalgona, The Glass Game, Squid Game ",
        answer: 2
      }
  ];

  const CORRECT_POINTS = 500;
  const MAX_QUESTIONS = 10;

  //arrow functions & notes used to define our trivia container question and answers behavior
  // Arrow Function Break Down:
  // 1. Remove the word "function" and place arrow between the argument and opening body bracket
  // 2. Remove the body braces and word "return" â€” the return is implied.
  // 3. Remove the argument parentheses
  beginGame = () => {
      questionCounter = 0;
      score = 0;
      availableQuestions = [...questions];
      console.log(availableQuestions);
      getNewQuestion();

      let playertime = setInterval(() => {
          Squidtimer-=5
          //console.log(Squidtimer);
          let Squidcount = document.getElementById("Squidtimer");
          //console.log(Squidcount);
          Squidcount.innerText = `Timer: ${Squidtimer}`
          if (Squidtimer < 0){
              clearInterval(playertime)
          }
      }, 1000);

  };
  
  getNewQuestion = () => {
      //Below code will send the player to the playerscores.html page to log in their name / initials
       if (availableQuestions.length === 0 || questionCounter > MAX_QUESTIONS) {
           return location.assign("playerscores.html")
       }        
      questionCounter++;
      squidQuestionCounter.innerText = questionCounter + "/" + MAX_QUESTIONS;

      const questionIndex = Math.floor(Math.random() * availableQuestions.length);
      currentQuestion = availableQuestions[questionIndex];
      question.innerText = currentQuestion.question;


      selections.forEach(choice => {
          const number = choice.dataset["number"];
          choice.innerHTML = currentQuestion["choice" + number];
      });
      //Remove the question from available questions
      availableQuestions.splice(questionIndex, 1);
      selectingAnswers = true;
  };
    
  selections.forEach(choice => {
      choice.addEventListener("click", e => {

    selectingAnswers = false;
    const selectedChoice = e.target;
    const selectedAnswer = selectedChoice.dataset["number"];
    //console.log(selectedAnswer == currentQuestion.answer);  
    
    //Define squidAnswers as incorrect but check for correct answers
    let squidAnswers = "incorrect";
    if (selectedAnswer == currentQuestion.answer) {
         squidAnswers = "correct";
    }
     //console.log(squidAnswers);

     if (squidAnswers === "correct") {
         incrementScore(CORRECT_POINTS);
     }

     //gives red-incorrect and green-incorrect when player chooses answers
     selectedChoice.parentElement.classList.add(squidAnswers);
     setTimeout(() => {
        selectedChoice.parentElement.classList.remove(squidAnswers);
        //Load New Question
        getNewQuestion();
      }, 1000);//sets a delay 
    });
  });

  incrementScore = num => {
    score += num;
    Squidscore.innerText = "Score: " + score;
  };
  

  beginGame();